Finding Aid for the Fugitive and Agrarian Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Fugitive Materials
  - Wiltshire, Susan Ford. “Aeneas in Tennessee: Vergil and the Vanderbilt Fugitives” in Vanderbilt Magazine, Fall, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - “Fugitive No More” in Vanderbilt Hustler, August 10, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Fugitive and Agrarian books in Vanderbilt Library - several lists (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Fugitive and Agrarian items offered for sale to Special Collections (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Fugitives - newspaper clippings (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Fugitives - newspaper clippings (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Agrarians
  - I’ll Take My Stand. Tate Authorization. 1930 2. Vanderbilt Masquerader, Vol. X, no.3, December 1933 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - “The Agrarians Today: a Symposium” in Shenandoah, Autumn 1952 (photocopy); “Dualisms in Agrarian Thought” by Virginia Rock reprinted from Mississippi Quarterly, XIII (Spring 1960) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - “Brief” by Rick Byrd for Vanderbilt Centennial History, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - “The Southern Agrarians” in New Boston Review, Vol. IV, no. III, December 1978 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Agrarian Symposium, 1980 - programs, Vanderbilt Alumnus, Vol. 66, no. 1, Winter 1981; Versus, April, 1980; newspaper articles (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - “ About Face or Forward March? Nashville Agrarians, Southern Liberals, and the 1930 Richmond Debate on the Future of the South” by John Kneebone in Virginia Cavalcade, Vol.36, no. 3, Winter, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - “The Twelve Apostles” by Hal Crowther in Oxford American January/February, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Walter Clyde Curry
  - “Walter Clyde Curry’s Last Lecture” by Dan D. Moore, (LSU) c, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Donald Davidson
  - Letter to Walter Clyde Curry, June 3, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - “Southern Progressivism” in Saturday Review of Literature, February 11, 1933 (photocopy) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - “Sectionalism in the United States” in Hound and Horn, July – September, 1933 (photocopy) (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - “The Trend of Literature: A Partisan View” in Culture in the South, ed. William T. Couch. Chapel Hill: UNC Pressw, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - “Agrarianism and Politics” in Review of Politics, April 1939 (photocopy) (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - “White Spirituals: The Choral Music of the South” in American Scholar, Autumn 1935 (photocopy) (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - “Regionalism as Social Science” in Southern Review, Autumn, 1937 (photocopy) (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - “The Class Approach to Southern Problems” in Southern Review, Autumn,1939 (photocopy) (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - “Mr. Babbitt at Philadelphia” in Southern Review, Spring 1941 (photocopy) (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - “The Mystery of the Agrarians: Facts and Illusions About Some Southern Writers” in The Saturday Review, January 23, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Doctor of Letters invitation to Davidson. Washington and Lee University, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Review of Regionalism in America, ed. by Merrill Jensen in American Literature,March 1952 (photocopy) (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Singin’ Billy – programs, April 23-26, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - “Regionalism” in Collier’s 1954 Year Book, ed. William T. Couch. NewYork: P. F. Collier and Son, 1954. (photocopy) (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Notebook. South Carolina Gazette, 1760 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Propaganda mailing, c, 1961 - 63 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Tribute program. Vanderbilt University Department of English, January 19, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Poem - “Gradual of the Northern Summer” and correspondence with Eleanor Scott Morse, 1964 - 1975 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Young, T. D. and Kirk, Russell. Introduction and Preface to The Tennessee, 1978 (photocopy) (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Offer of books from Fugitive Books, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - “Traditions of Southern Thought: Frederick Douglass and Donald Davidson” Conference, 1992 at Vanderbilt University (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Murphy, Paul. “The Social Memory of the South: Donald Davidson and the Tennessee Past” in Tennessee Historical Quarterly, Fall, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Poetry Reviews - newspaper clippings (43 items) (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Student Paper by Sarah McCanless (Howell) (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Student Papers of Adelle Dudney, 1928 - 1930 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Student Paper of Sally Rodes (Lee), 1952 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Davidson, Theresa Sherrer - printed copy and transparency of her illustrations for The Tennessee (Box 2, Folder 37)
- William Yandell Elliott
  - Letter to Donald Davidson, June 9, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - “The Metaphysics of Duguit’s Pragmatic Conception of Law” reprinted from Political Science Quarterly, Vol. XXXVIII, no. 4, December, 1922; “ Mussolini, Prophet of the Pragmatic Era in Politics” reprinted from Political Science Quarterly,Vol. XLI, no. 2, June, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - “Vers Une Nouvelle Constitution” extrait du Recueil d’Etudes enl’honneur d’Edouard Lambert (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Address to the graduating class of 1960, the Webb School, Bell Buckle, Tennessee (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Articles, obituary (Box 2, Folder 42)
- John Gould Fletcher
  - Correspondence concerning his letters (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Sidney M. Hirsch
  - Letter from Merrill Moore, January 13, 1950; Art and Mysticism - cover (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Hirsch family tree since, 1790 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Lyle Lanier
  - Articles, obituary, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Andrew Lytle
  - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - “The Passion of Alex Maury” book review in The New Republic, January 2, 1935 “Congratulations” by Stark Young (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - “The Quality of the South” in National Review, March 8, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - “Man or Symbol?” book review of Brainard Cheney’s This is Adam in The New Republic, December 6, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence with Richard Sanders re: A Wake for the Living including publisher blurb and photograph, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Symposium participant “The Changing South: Rural to Urban” 1980 “Andrew Nelson Lytle: A Celebration” Sewanee, Tennessee, December 3, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Articles by and about Lytle in The Chatttahoochee Review Vol. I, no. 1, Spring, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - “An Afternoon on the Porch with Andrew Lytle” by Douglas Paschall in Touchstone: the Magazine of the Tennessee Humanities Council, Number 8, Fall, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Andrew Lytle issue Horns of Plenty, with correspondence, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Newspaper articles and reviews (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper articles and reviews (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Newspaper articles and reviews (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Newspaper articles and reviews (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Newspaper articles and reviews (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Newspaper articles and reviews (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Merrill Moore
  - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence - Helen Frank (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence - Virginia Campbell Johns (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - “Poems from the Fugitive”, 1922 - 1926 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - “It’s a Good Deal Later Than You Think” reprinted from Avenue, June 4, 1934
    - “Ego” reprinted from Life and Letters To-Day, October, 1938
  - “Eight Sonnets” reprinted from the January number of The Sewanee Review, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - “Note on a Limerick” reprint from The American Imago, Vol. 13, no.2 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - “Notes on Re-Reading Dr. Hanns Sachs’ Last Book” reprint from The American Imago, Vol. 11, no. 1, Spring, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Medical Journal articles - Alcoholism (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Medical Journal articles - Conchology (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Medical Journal articles (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Medical Journal articles (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Medical Journal articles (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Medical Journal articles (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Personal and Biographical items, 1914, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Personal and Biographical - Military Service (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Personal and Biographical - “Success” by John Trotwood Moore (M.M’s father) with Biographical note, J.T.M. (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Personal and Biographical - articles (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Merrill Moore
  - “Merrill Moore” by Louis Untermeyer reprinted from the January Number of The Sewanee Review, 1935; “Three Younger Poets” by Louis Untermeyer in The English Journal, December 1932 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - “Dawn Honey” musical composition - words by Merrill Moore, music by Ives Hendrick, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - “The Mental Measure of Merrill Moore” by F. L. Wells reprinted from Life and Letters To-Day, Vol. 21, no. 19, pages 27 - 36, March 1939 (London) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - “Poet and Psychiatrist: Merrill Moore” by Henry W. Wells reprinted from The Hopkins Review, Vol. VI, no. 1, Fall 1952 (Baltimore, Maryland) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper articles and reviews; travel literature (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Vanderbilt Centennial History file - newspaper articles (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Book reviews (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Book promotional materials (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Book promotional materials (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Eulogy and Elegy by Michel Farrano - inscribed to Anne Leslie Moore (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Obituaries in Harvard Medical Alumni Bulletin, October 1957; February 1958 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Obituary in The New England Journal of Medicine, October 31, 1957, vol. 257, no.18 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Obituaries, 1957 (1) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Obituaries, 1957 (2) (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Herman Clarence Nixon
  - “Social Security for Southern Farmers” from Southern Policy Papers No. 2, Chapel Hill: The University of North Carolina Press, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Frank Lawrence Owsley
  - Newspaper articles and reviews; booklet Alabama Academy of Distinquished Authors Inductees, 1982 - 1986 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- John Crowe Ransom
  - Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Incoming correspondence – Delmore Schwartz, July 5, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Letter to Robie Macauley, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Poem “As We Two Walked at Dusk” (never published typescript) (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - “The State and the Land” in New Republic, February 17, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - “Address to the Scholars of New England” (Harvard Phi Beta Kappa Poem, June 23, 1939) in The Kenyon Review (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Tribute from the Community of Letters, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Program “Martin College presents John Crowe Ransom” Friday, April 28, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Memorial Lectures. Program, Gambier, Ohio, April 3 - 5, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - “The Kenyon Review and the Rockefeller Foundation” Rockefeller Archives Center Newslette r, Fall 1991, pp. 3 - 4. (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Newspaper articles and reviews, 1930’s - 1950’s (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Newspaper articles and reviews (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Newspaper articles and reviews (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Newspaper articles and reviews, 1974 - 1089 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Response to biography, Gentleman in a Dustcoat by Thomas Daniel Young from Brainard Cheney, Elizabeth Spencer; Ransom’s grandparents’ marriage certificate, 1851 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Vanderbilt Centennial History file (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Giles County, Tennessee Historical Marker, and invitation, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Photograph (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Library of Congress Contemporary Recordings. Text. Ransom, Warren, Tate, and others (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Laura Riding
  - Newspaper articles (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Obituary in The New York Times, September 4, 1991 A16 (photocopy) (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Allen Tate
  - Parthenia and Other Poems (1922). Photocopies from original in the Vanderbilt University English Department, November 9, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - “Putting Agrarianism into Practice” by John Thompson in The Tennessean Magazine,Sunday June 27, 1937 (includes photograph of Tate and his wife Caroline Gordon and Mr. and Mrs. Ford Madox Ford) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - “The Critic Behind Barbed Wire: If He Wishes He Can End His Self-Imposed Internment” by Herbert J. Mueller in Saturday Review of Literature, September 25, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Tate’s Venus” by Nicholson Adams. Review of Tate’s translation of The Vigil of Venus, offprint from The Quarterly Review of Literature, March 1944, Vol. I, no. 2. Inscribed by Tate (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - “The Elizabeth Madox Roberts Papers” by Allen Tate in Library of Congress Quarterly Journal, Vol. I, no. 2, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - “The Fathers and Realistic Fiction” review by Arthur Mizener in Accent, 1947 (photocopy) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - “The Hovering Fly” Cummington Press Prospectus, October 1948 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - “Fragment of a Meditation/MCMXXXXVII” Christmas Card from Caroline and Allen Tate, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - “Dr. Johnson on Religious Poetry” Broadside lecture announcement, May 15, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Program - Kansas Writer’s Conference, University of Kansas, June 8 - 21, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - “Is Literary Criticism Possible?” Typescript, 1950 - 51 (17 pages) (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - “Allen Tate est à Paris” clipping from Le Figaro Litterâire, 24 Mai 1952. Extrait de “Ode aux morts confédérés” translated by Jacques and Raissa Maritain (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1968 - 69, 3 items (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence to Thomas Daniel Young and others, 1959 - 1981 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Vanderbilt Alumni Records and information (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Vanderbilt Centennial History file (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Collected Poems, 1919 - 1976 - Duplicate proofs, author’s set (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Box 6 Allen Tate
  - Poems “The Eye” and “Mother and Son” typescripts (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - “Allen Tate y el mito del Sur” by Alejandro Oliveros, 1952 (photocopy) (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - “Christ and the Unicorn”, 1954 (photocopy of offprint) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - “Mere Literature and the Lost Traveller” C.C. Williamson Memorial Lecture, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - “A Trivial Meditation” in The Sewanee News, December 1970 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - 75th Birthday Celebration, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Mountain Summer, Sewanee, 1975 (Tate - Poetry Contest Judge) (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - “Dead Confederate Ode” in National Lampoon, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Review of Collected Essays by Carlos Baker (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Reviews of Essays of Four Decades and others (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Reviews of The Forlorn Demon: Didactic and Critical Essays, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Reviews of Tate’s Poems, 1922 - 1947 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Reviews of On the Limits of Poetry (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Reviews of Stonewall Jackson and Jefferson Davis (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Reviews of Collected Poems of John Peale Bishop (edited by Tate) (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Reviews of A Southern Vanguard ( edited by Tate) (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Reviews of T.S. Eliot: The Man and His Work (edited by Tate) (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Reviews (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Reviews (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - “In Memoriam (1899 - 1979)” (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - “Allen Tate... Man of Letters” by Eve Zibart in The Tennessean, February 11, 1979 “Allen Tate in Minneapolis” in The Boston Review, April/May 1979, Vol. IV, no. 5 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Obituaries, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Prizes won by Tate - newspaper articles (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Evelyn Scott Fund. Letter of appeal (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Newspaper articles (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Newspaper articles (Box 6, Folder 26)
- John Donald Wade
  - Bidding for Distinction: John Wade’s Georgia Review by Anne Rittenberry. Research Paper, summer 1993 for English 598 at the University of Tennessee at Chattanooga (Box 6, Folder 27)
- Robert Penn Warren
  - Correspondence, 1927 - 1966 and undated (25 items) (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence outgoing to Dr. Kate Savage Zerfoss, November 19, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence incoming from Donald Davidson (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence outgoing to Maria Garcia, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Typed note to Bill (William Meredith), June 5, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Poems. Bound unpublished manuscript/with letters to William Meredith (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Poem, “Twice Born” signed galley proof (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Poems published in The New Yorker, Washington Post Magazine, August 3, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Poem, “Dream of a Dream” holiday greeting card from G.K. Hall and Co., 1976 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - “Dream of a Dream” publishers papers, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 38)
- Robert Penn Warren
  - (All the King’s Men) Willie Stark - Musical Drama - libretto by Carlisle Floyd (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - All the King’s Men - Dramatic Version: Dallas Theater Center (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - All the King’s Men - review; reviews of The Cave and Then and Now: The Personal Past in the Poetry of Robert Penn Warren by Floyd Watkins (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - All the King’s Men - “The Longs of Louisiana” in Sunday Times Magazine, December 7, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - All the King’s Men - Limited Editions Club Letter, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Brother to Dragons - fragment - typescript (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Brother to Dragons: A Tale in Verse and Voices (typed manuscript) master copy, original with corrections by Warren, and notes by William Meredith (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Brother to Dragons - play - mimeographed typed manuscript, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - “William Faulkner and His South” University of Virginia Peters Rushton Lecture, March 13, 1951 - typescript and announcement (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - “The World of Daniel Boone” in Holiday, 1963 (photocopy) (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - “Malcolm X: Mission and Meaning” in Yale Review: A National Quarterly, Winter, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - “Hawthorne was Relevant” National Medal for Literature, acceptance speech, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - “Is Poetry Relevant” in The English Exchange,”, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - “A Reporter at Large: Jefferson Davis Gets His Citizenship Back” in The New Yorker, February 25, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - “A Reminiscence” in Nashville: The Faces of Two Centuries edited by John Egerton, 1980 (photocopy) (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - “The Genius of Katherine Anne Porter” in Saturday Review, December 1980 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - “Red Warren, Rebel in the Ivy League” in Nashville Tennessean Magazine, Sunday, December 27, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Program, Fiftieth Anniversary Dinner of the Pulitzer Prizes, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Vanderbilt Poetry Review, Robert Penn Warren Issue, 1977 (signed by Warren on the title page) (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - “Toward Sunset at a Great Height” in The Vanderbilt Hustler, Vol. 88, no. 51, April 8, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - “Robert Penn Warren at 72” by Joseph Rosenbloom in The Boston Globe, April 17, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - White House and National Endowment for the Humanities Invitations, June 9, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - 75th Birthday Symposium at the University of Kentucky, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Symposia honoring Robert Penn Warren - press releases and newspaper articles (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - “Robert Penn Warren’s Courage” book review by James Dickey in Saturday Review, August 1980 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - MacArthur Foundation Award. Newspaper articles, June 1981 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - “Stories of Deep Delight” by Alan Cheuse in the Boston Globe, June 4, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - “Robert Penn Warren” by Carl Tucker in Saturday Review, July 1981 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Poet Laureate - newspaper clippings, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Program - “Robert Penn Warren: A Hometown Symposium, Oct. 15 - 17, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Article and photograph from Vanity Fair, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - “Library of Congress Issues Poster Honoring Robert Penn Warren” in Library of Congress Information Bulletin, Vol. 46, no. 15, April 13, 1987 “Lecture by Robert Penn Warren to be Presented at the Library” in Library of Congress Information Bulletin, April 20, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - “Robert Penn Warren and the South” by Lewis Simpson in Touchstone: The Magazine of the Tennessee Humanities Council, Number 16, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Invitation and newspaper article - RPW birthplace dedication, April 21, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - “Manuscripts, letters enhance Warren Collection” in Chronicle, Vol. 15, no. 1, Winter, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Catalog 38, Robert Penn Warren, Selections from the Collection of Stuart Wright, H.E. Turlington Books, Pittsboro, North Carolina, Fall, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 36)
- Robert Penn Warren
  - “A Place to Think: The Robert Penn Warren Center for the Humanities Offers Faculty a Chance to Study Together” in Vanderbilt Magazine, Spring, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - “Family donates Robert Penn Warren Library” in Western Kentucky University Alumni Magazine, Winter, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 2 brochures from Western Kentucky University:“Remembrance of Robert Penn Warren”; “A Guide to Warren Country” (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - 3 articles from Southern Review, Autumn 1994 (photocopies): “Notes on an Unpublished Robert Penn Warren” by James A. Perkins; “Episode in the Dime Store” by Robert Penn Warren;“The Gathering of the Fugitives: a Recollection” by Louis D. Rubin, Jr. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Reviews of Robert Penn Warren Talking and A Place to Come To (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Reviews (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper articles (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper articles (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper articles (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper articles (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper and magazine articles (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper and magazine articles (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper and magazine articles (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Vanderbilt Centennial History file (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Order of Service commemorating the life and work of Robert Penn Warren, 1905 - 1989 at Benton Chapel, Vanderbilt University, November 8, 1989; Announcement of the service and purchase of Warren archive for Vanderbilt University (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Obituaries - Reaction 1989, April 24, 1905 - September 15, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Obituaries - Reaction, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Obituaries - Reaction, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Obituaries and photograph of Warren with 2 of his students in, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Jesse Ely Wills
  - Papers - letters and poems (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Old Oak and Coffee House Papers by Jesse E. Wills, 1930’s and 1940’s (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - “Poet in the Money Making Business” by Louise Davis in The Nashville Tennessean, January 17, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Newspaper articles and reviews (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - “In What Dreams” poem to Jesse Ely Wills by Merrill Moore in Bulletin of the American Iris Society, April 1955, No. 137, p.4 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - 75th Birthday - invitation, poem, newspaper clippings (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Obituaries and tributes (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - “Saudacao ao Prof Evaldo Coutinho” pamphlet by Alan Costa, Recife, 1982 (Vanderbilt, Ph.D. dissertation on Jesse Wills: The Biography of a Fugitive: an Evaluation of the Life and Work of Jesse E. Wills, 1983) (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - “A Grandson’s Perspective” by Ridley Wills, III in The Bell Ringer (Montgomery Bell Academy), 1980 (Box 8, Folder 28)
- Ridley Wills
  - The Golden Mean (1923) with Allen Tate - 5 pages, typescript with corrections (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - “The Dog Wagon, Allen Tate, Ridley Wills, and the Golden Mean” by Kep Thorpe, A’20 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    Associates of the Fugitives and Agrarians and other southern writers
- William T. Bandy
  - Letter from Allen Tate, April 11, 1964 “Memories of Montparnasse: Ford Madox Ford’s Sonnet Parties” in Cumberland Poetry Review,Vol. III, no. 2, Spring 1984 (photocopy) (Box 8, Folder 31)
- Richmond Croom Beatty
  - “A Personal Memoir of the Agrarians,” in Shenandoah 3, Summer 1952, pp. 111 - 13 (photocopy) (Box 8, Folder 32)
- Melvin E. Bradford